So friends, ICICI Lombard has
disclosed its quarter four numbers.
So let's see what's in the
quarter four numbers. I'll compare them
with market estimates and
explain how the company's numbers are
looking. And let me tell you, the
company has also announced a dividend of
₹ per share. The company has
announced a dividend for which the
record date will be.
A GGM will be held by the company in the coming days, in
which you will see the company mentioning the record date.
Let's look at the numbers. They are
given in lakhs for the database.
I'll convert them to crores and
explain how you are seeing the company's numbers. So, if we
talk about the last quarter, the company's
total income approximated near Rs.
5161 crore. So, if we look at it
year after
year, you are seeing a slight decline in the company's revenue year after year.
You can almost say  There
is a decline of around 2 percent in the total income of the company year after year.
If we
go quarter by quarter, then you will see a rise of
around 3 percent in the total income of the company quarter after quarter.
But when you
go to see the premium income of the company
because the main revenue of the company is being
generated from here, then
in the last quarter the premium income of the company was
approx.
pass, whereas if you see now, it has increased to around 4767 crores. So
if you are looking here, then
you will come to know that you will see the net
premium income of the company increasing
year after year. Let us see
what are the expenses of the company. If we
talk about the last quarter, then
in the last quarter the company's expenses were around 4587 crores,
last year it was around 3976 crores,
whereas if you see now, then
you will see the company's expenses around 4600 crores. So if you
look at the expenses of the company, then
you will get to see the expenses of the company are very high in this section
because as I told you, the
revenue of the company is around 2 percent.  It is
seen falling for the year but
when we go into the expenses, you can see the company's
expenses increasing by almost 15 to 16 percent as compared to last year,
which is slightly negative here. Let us see
what the net profit of the company is. If we
talk about the last quarter, then in the last quarter the company's
profit was around Rs 431 crore. Last year it was
around Rs 436 crore. If we look at it now, you will see the
company's profit
increasing to Rs 519 crore. If we look at it year after year,
you will see a significant increase in the company's profit year after year. There is a
jump of almost around Rs 19 percent. So
your question should arise that how has the company's
profit increased when the company's
revenue falls at Rs 2 and the company's expenses are
also very high. You
see more at Rs 15, then the
company's profit should fall, so
how are you seeing the company's profit increasing? The
reason behind it is the company's
expenses because other  If you look at the expenses, then the
total expenses of the company, including all other things and
provision vision, then
in the last quarter the company incurred around ₹51 crore,
last year it was around ₹897 crore, whereas
in this quarter it was only around ₹
97 crore. So, you see here that where ₹
897 crore was spent last year, if you look at it now,
you see only around ₹97 crore,
due to which you see the net profit of the company
increasing.
Because if you remove the net profit and
look at the operating profit of the company, which is
before expenses, then
in the last quarter the profit was ₹415 crore, last year it was
around ₹1278 crore, whereas if you look at it now,
you see only around ₹561 crore. So, if you
look at it year after year,
you see the profit of the company falling almost to around ₹55 crore, whereas as we
go quarter by quarter,
you see the profit of the company
increasing quarter by quarter. Let us
see what is the EPS of the company.  If we
talk about the last quarter, then
in the last quarter the company's EPS was
around 878 paise, last year it was 8.90 paise, if we
look at it now, you will see it around 10.5, so you have seen the
company's EPS
increasing quarter by quarter year after year
because EPS is basically
calculated on the basis of net profit and
you are seeing the net profit increasing, so
if you look at it overall,
you will see a bit of mixed numbers
because the net revenue of the company has been
seen falling year after year but
you are seeing the premium income increasing
and if you look at the operating profit,
you have seen it falling there
but the net income has been seen increasing, so
you are seeing a bit of mixed numbers, let's see
how the market reacts,
but the company showed a net profit of Rs 519
crore, the market was also expecting the company
's profit to be around Rs 510 crore,
but due to expenses, such an expectation was there,
it is a bit difficult to say that the market was assuming that there would be some
expenses on this.  It is
difficult to say whether there will be more or not, so let's
see how the market responds,
but according to me there are a little mixed numbers, let's see
how the market responds, so that's all
for today, if you liked the video then
please like it and also subscribe to the channel, thank you.